<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter version="5.0" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
         xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
         xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
         xmlns:svg="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg"
         xmlns:m="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
         xmlns:html="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"
         xmlns:db="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook">
    <title>Introduction</title>

    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata align="center" fileref="../common/art/INDIfaceH.png"
                   scalefit="1" width="6in"></imagedata>
      </imageobject>
    </mediaobject>

    <section>
      <title>Overview</title>

      <para><trademark>Eclipse Identity Recognition Corporation</trademark>
      provides <emphasis>Personal Identity Recognition</emphasis> via its
      face-based analytics known as INDIface. It is used to detect faces and
      facial features and then generate face templates for searching and
      matching. In addition, the INDIface analytics can also determine skin
      tone, upper and lower clothes color, and an estimated height of a
      person. The INDIbase system provides for the enrollment, storage,
      management, retrieval, and matching of INDIface templates. INDIbase also
      manages facial and other images as well as personal identification and
      characteristic data.</para>

      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="art/SDK1-Blocks.svg" scalefit="1" width="6in"></imagedata>
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>

      <para>In addition to providing the base for EclipseIR's applications,
      the INDIface Software Development Kit (SDK) allows OEM developers to
      create custom applications using EclipseIR's technology. The INDIface
      SDK is currently for Windows-based stand-alone systems up to 50,000
      enrollments. In the short term, the INDIface SDK will be made available
      on most Linux- or BSD-based platforms in addition to Microsoft Windows.
      At the same time, configuration will be taken from INI files rather than
      the Windows registry. EclipseIR also plans to embed portions of its
      technologies in “Smart Cameras” pushing more capability to the edge of
      the network. EclipseIR will continue to develop more face-based
      analytics (such as demographic estimates) and other technologies for
      personal identity recognition, for example, gait recognition. As well,
      EclipseIR will pursue complementary technologies, such as the vehicular
      identity recognition. These expanded capabilities will be included in
      the SDK and/or API is appropriate to allow third-party developers to
      include them in their custom applications. At the moment the binary
      implementation of the SDK is a Windows console application
      (IfSearch.exe) and a few DLLs.</para>

      <section>
        <title>C<superscript>3</superscript></title>

        <subtitle>Configuration, Control, Command</subtitle>

        <para>The behavior of the INDIface SDK is currently controlled via the
        Windows registry. In the future we will add the ability to use INI
        and/or XML configuration files. The default is
        <filename>HKCU/Software/EclipseIR/IfSearch</filename>. Most options
        can also be specified on the command line.</para>

        <para>Most of the configuration values are "volatile," that is they
        can be changed in the registry at any time and the executing IfSearch
        will automatically pick up the changes. Things that are not volatile
        will be documented, but it is mainly in the selection of detectors and
        location of initialization files.</para>

        <para><informalfigure>
            <para><mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                  <imagedata fileref="art/SDK1-Flow.svg" scalefit="1"
                             width="6in"></imagedata>
                </imageobject>
              </mediaobject></para>
          </informalfigure></para>
      </section>

      <section xml:id="secImageInput">
        <title>Image Input</title>

        <para>The SDK will take its input images from an IP camera or a "hot
        directory."</para>

        <section>
          <title>Live IP Input</title>

          <para>Specify the input URL with "http" as the scheme, user name and
          password if needed, host address, and a path and file name that will
          result in a single frame to be returned to IfSearch. For example
          <userinput>/Input/URL=http://demo:demo@192.168.1.90/jpg/image.jpg</userinput>.
          Most of the work so far has been with Axis 210 and 240 and a trial
          with Arecont, but any ONVIF compliant camera should work.</para>
        </section>

        <section>
          <title>Hot Directory Input</title>

          <para>Specify the input URL with "dir" as the scheme; user name,
          password, and host are ignored; the relative path starts after the
          slash following the host. To be an official URL, drive separating
          colons should be replaced with vertical stiles and Windows-style
          backslashes should be replaced with forward slashes; but we'll work
          either way. Examples:</para>

          <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
              <para><userinput>/Input/URL=dir:///.</userinput> reads from the
              current directory</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para><userinput>/Input/URL=dir:////InputImages</userinput>
              reads from <filename>\InputImages</filename> on the current
              drive</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para><userinput>/Input/URL=dir:///T|/Input/Images/Today</userinput>
              reads from <filename>T:\Input\Images\Today</filename></para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para><userinput>/Input/URL=dir:///T:\Input\Images\Today</userinput>
              ditto.</para>
            </listitem>
          </itemizedlist>

          <para>Hot directories have several advantages:</para>

          <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
              <para>When all images have been processed, you can start
              processing again-mostly useful for testing or
              demonstrating.</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Images can be deleted from the directory after they have
              been processed.</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Image files can be moved to a separate directory after
              they have been processed.</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Processing can be started on an empty directory and image
              files are processed as they are dropped in to the "hot"
              directory.</para>
            </listitem>
          </itemizedlist>
        </section>
      </section>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>Installation</title>

      <para>The SDK distribution is in a ZIP file with the default directory
      structure. Unzip it to the location of you liking.</para>

      <section>
        <title>Directory Structure</title>

        <para>This is the default directory structure. If necessary some of
        the directories can be eliminated or moved to other locations with the
        new locations specified in the registry.</para>

        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>./INDIface/bin-w32 contains the 32-bit Windows IfSearch
            executable and its libraries along with necessary 3rd party
            libraries.</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>./INDIface/data/Face1 contains the INDIface template
            generation data files.</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>./INDIface/detectors contains Detectors.XML and the actual
            detector XML data.</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>./INDIface/bin-w32/imageformats contains image file format
            translators that will be used by IfSearch at start up.</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>./INDIface/bin-w32/imageformats/extras contains other image
            file format translators.</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>/INIDface/bin-w32/sqldrivers will contain SQL database
            interface translators in the future.</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>./INDIface/FaceBase will contain person records and enrolled
            faces (normalized images and templates).</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>./Sample/Input contains optional sample input data.</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>./Sample/Output contains optional sample output data.</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>./SampleInput/SampleFaceBase contains an optional sample
            FaceBase.</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>

        <para>You may want to add W:\hatever\INDIface\bin to the system PATH
        so you can start IfSearch from any current directory.</para>
      </section>
    </section>
  </chapter>
